+90 (536) 653-1986 mahdi.mehrizi@gmail.com https://mehrizi.github.io/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahdi-mehrizi/

Mahdi Mehrizi

Summary

In my past three years, I have developed or coordinated variety of web-based solutions using Laravel and React/Vue. In every project or contract, I try to R&D first instead of following my common established developing routines. It is about 15 years that I am making a living by web development but programming is an always changing technology even most of the principles rarely change, and if you don't adapt and learn continuously, you are not a good programmer. I have a strong background in mathematics, algorithms and design patterns. I believe this knowledge is a must for continuous successful development and delivery in big projects. Otherwise as time passes more and more bugs and problems arise and gets to the point to either fail the project or recode the whole project using these principles.

I am a very passionate person and like to be a part of a team rather than working remote well-paid projects alone or in small team. In my past working experiences, bests were those that I was working as part of big teams.

I am currently looking for such opportunities in passionate and live team work environment and if my technical expertise matches your needs, it is an honor to be considered for such a position.

Skill Highlights

Javascript (expert): ES6&JSX&TSX, React&Recoil, Vue, TDD (Dusk)

UI (experienced): HTML&CSS3, SCSS, LESS, MUI, Vuetify

PHP (expert): Laravel, graphQL (Lighthouse), Sail, Telescope, Sanctum, Passport, Scout

Databases(Intermediate): MySQL, Mongo, AWS aurora and RDS

devOps (beginner): AWS, Docker, Docker-compose Managerial(Intermediate): SCRUM, ClickUp, Atlasian

Other hard skills: Java, JavaFX

Public Repos:

- The Multi Event React Calendar Component
 - o Demo: https://mehrizi.github.io/multi-event
 - o Github: https://github.com/mehrizi/multi-event
- My CV:
 - o Demo: https://mehrizi.github.io/keyboard/
 - o Github: https://github.com/mehrizi/keyboard

Experiences

Backend Developer - 02/2023 to 11/2023

Brodeus, Izmir, Turkey

Bootstrapping and developing backend API for an NFT football game:

- Backend: GraphQL (Lighthouse), Dockerised Laravel10, Sail, Sanctum, AWS
- Frontend: React&Recoil, MUI, Vite

Fullstack Web Developer - 01/2022 to 02/2023

Technical Inspection Service Organization, Germany (remote)

I hold meetings with client and based on the use story I developed:

- Backend: Dockerised Laravel9, Scout, Sail, Sanctum, Inertia
- Frontend: React&Recoil, Inertia, MUI, TDD(Dusk, Selenium), Inertia&Vite

FullStack Web Developer - 04/2021 to 04/2022

TEEWS (Tehran early earthquake warning system)

I developed the monitoring interface for the project showing all station details, etc.

- Backend: Laravel8, Passport, Docker&Docker-compose, mongo, TDD (PHPunit)
- Frontend: Vue, Vuetify

FullStack Web Developer - 09/2020 to 06/2022

Sapiominds TestTool, US (remote)

I hold meetings with client and based on real user feedbacks and feature requests we developed a very multimedia rich testing platform:

- Backend: Laravel8, Sanctum Docker&Docker-compose, AWS
- Frontend: Vue, Vuetify

Web Developer - 11/2018 to 06/2021

Part Software Group

We have developed several professional WP themes for different public websites of the big holding. Some like https://signal.ir had detailed graphs and data display. I was moderating a team of 4 in the last year.

Backend: WP SDK, Sage

• Frontend: SCSS, react, WP Gutenberg Block SDK

FullStack Web Developer - 02/2013 to 10/2018

https://webyka.com

We developed a very full functional SaaS CMS with ecommerce modules and multimedia features. I sometimes moderated 4 teammates for delivering features to deadlines.

- Backend: Codeigniter
- Frontend: ES6, AngularJS (Angular 1.7), Material Design, SCSS, LESS

Realtyna inc.

We developed a very full functional Joomla&WP Component&Themes, respectively. It offered over 10 different modules and addons to fascilitate realestate agents or companies business. We built a team of 15 developers starting a team 3.

- Backend: WP SDK, Joomla SDK, API integrations(bill.com, payment gateways, etc.)
- Frontend: jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap

Free Lance Web Developer - 2007 to 2010

Those early days....

Education



Master of Physics, 2010 (Resigned)

And this was the time I decided to be a complete Nerd, even I ranked 7th nationally in the master entry exam.



B.Sc. of Physics, 2005 - 2010

Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran.

GPA: 17.74/20



Secondary School Diploma, 2001 - 2005

NODET (National Organization for Development of Exceptional Talents), Mashhad, Iran.

GPA: 17.75/20

Languages

Persian: Native

English: Fluent in speaking, listening, good at reading and intermediate in writing:

TOEFL(iBT): 92/120 (10/2009)